以下内容提供
the following content is provided under
CreativeCommons许可您的支持
a Creative Commons license your support
将帮助MITOpenCourseWare继续
will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to
提供高质量的教育资源
offer high quality educational resources
免费
for free
捐款或查看额外的捐款
to make a donation or to view additional
数百个麻省理工学院课程的材料
materials from hundreds of MIT courses
访问位于ocw.mit.edu的麻省理工学院开放式课件
visit MIT opencourseware at ocw.mit.edu
好吧现在聚集图表所以这个
okay now clustering for graphs so this
这是一个重要的话题之一
is a topic this is one of the important
你可以尝试用图表做的事情
things you can try to do with a graph so
你有一个大图，让我有种
you have a large graph let me kind of
将它分成两个群可以，所以你
divide it into two clusters okay so you
得到一个巨大的图形，然后将工作就是
get a giant graph and then the job is to
从中得出一些意义
make some sense out of it and one
可能的步骤是能够细分
possible step is to be able to subdivide
如果我看到这里有一个切口
it if as I see here there's a cut
在两个相当相等的部分之间
between two reasonably equal parts of
图表合理地相同
the graph reasonably reasonably same
大小，因此该图表可以
size and therefore that graph could be
两部分研究所以问题是
studied in two pieces so the question is
你如何通过a找到这样的切割
how do you find such a cut by a by a
算法什么是一个算法，将
algorithm what's an algorithm that would
发现这样切，所以这是一个问题
find that cut so the so that's a problem
让我们说我们正在寻找两个四个
let's say we're looking for two four
四个两个集群我们可以寻找更多
four two clusters we could look for more
集群，但让我们说我们想看
clusters but let's say we want to look
对于两个集群，我们在尝试什么
for two clusters so what are we trying
我们要尽量减少这个
to do we're trying to minimize so this
是问题，所以我们寻找发现
is the problem then so we look for find
位置x和y让我们说两个
positions x and y let's say two which
将成为中心，可以这么说
will be the center's so to speak of the
而且真的只是这些点是啊
and really it's just these points yeah
这样就可以得到数据了
that so that the data is the points and
边缘一直是节点和
the edges as always the nodes and the
边虽然所以问题是找到x
edges though so the problem is to find x
和y以便最小化
and y so that to minimize
所以这是AI与X点的距离
so it's a distance of points AI from X
也许应该强调我们处于高位
maybe should emphasize we're in high
尺寸加上其他的距离
dimensions plus the distance of other
因此AI将成为这些点
points so the AI will be these points
这些节点和bi将是这些
these nodes and the bi will be these
节点加上BI减去y的平方和
nodes plus the sum of BI minus y squared
你这里了解规则
and you understand the rule here that
蜜蜂的A联盟
the together the the A's Union the bees
给我所有节点，我想是
give me all nodes and I guess to be
完成a的a与a的交叉
complete the a's the a's intersect the
蜜蜂是空的只是你期望的
bees is empty just just what you expect
我把A和B分成了
I'm dividing the A's and the B's into
两组，我正在选择x和ay
two groups and I'm picking an x and a y
因此，这些群体的中心
sort of at the center of those groups so
这是最低限度，所以我想
that that is a minimum so I want to
最小化，也许我想
minimize and also I probably want to
施加一些条件的数量
impose some condition that the number of
A的是相当接近的数
A's is reasonably close to the number of
蜜蜂换句话说，我不想只是
bees in other words I don't want just
那将是一个和所有其余的
that to be the a and all the rest to be
蜜蜂不会是一个
the bees that would be not a
令人满意的聚类我正在寻找
satisfactory clustering I'm looking for
群集是大小合适的群集
clusters that are good sized clusters so
最小化，所以有很多
minimize that okay so there are a lot of
有些不同的算法
different algorithms to do it some are
更直接地攻击这个问题
more directly attacking this problem
其他人使用我们关联的矩阵
others use matrices that we associate
用图，从而让我告诉你
with the graph so let me tell you about
两个或三个
two or three
那些算法和你，如果你已经
those algorithms and and you if you've
看过本研究有一个图表课程
seen studied had a course in graph
理论你可能已经看过了
theory this you may already have seen
这个问题首先是问题
this problem first question would be
假设我认为这些是A和
suppose I decide these are the A's and
那些是蜜蜂或其他一些
those are the bees or some other
决定可能是其他一些
decision yeah probably some other
决定我不想解决
decisions I don't want to solve the
我开始之前的问题
problem before I even start
所以一些A和一些B会是什么
so some A's and some B's what would be
你曾经是X的最佳选择
the best choice of the X once you've
决定A和什么是
decided on the A's and what would be the
在Y的最佳选择，一旦你决定
best choice of the Y once you've decided
在B上，以便我们可以回答这个问题
on the B's so so that we can answer that
问我们是否知道这两个问题
question just if we knew the the two
小组我们可以看到他们应该在哪里
groups we could see where they should be
以第一组为中心
centered with the first group centered
在X，第二组以Y和为中心
at X the second group centered at Y and
什么是我的中心让我们说
what is centering me so let's just say
所以我想我在这里说的是这样的
so I think what I'm saying here is so
考虑到一个是A的，这是一个一上来
given the a's the a's this is a one up
说AK什么是最好的就是最好的
to say a k what is the best is the best
x只是为了使那部分正确而且
x to just to make that part right and
答案是你知道吗？
the answer is do do you know
几何上X应该在这里X是
geometrically what X should be here X is
所以，如果我有一堆积分和
the so if I have a bunch of points and
我正在寻找中间的那些
I'm looking for the middle of those
将X点指向一个好的X点
points the point X a good point X to say
好吧，这是它的中间部分
okay that's the middle it'll make the
我认为平方距离的总和
sum of the distances I think squared I
希望我是对的
hope I'm right about that
至少X是什么是什么
a minimum what's the what is X it is the
质心质心是X字
the centroid centroid is the word X is
质心
the centroids
的的A的，什么是
of the of the A's and what is the
质心让我们看得好，也许我没有
centroid let's see well maybe I don't
知道x和y我们是不是一个好选择
know if x and y we're a good choice but
让我看看我猜它是什么
look let me see what I guess it's the
平均值a它是A的总和
average a it's the sum of the A's of
这些A是那些是矢量的
these A's those are those are vectors of
当然，由A的I数除以
course divided by the number of A's I
我想我其实很快
think actually I was just quickly
今天早上回顾所以我不是
reviewing this morning so I'm not
完全在这个质心的顶部，我是什么
totally on top of this centroid what I'm
打算谈谈我的算法
going to talk the algorithm that I'm
要谈的是K井K.
going to talk about is the K well K
意味着它总是在这里被召唤
means it's always called and here it
将是K将是我刚才拥有的两个
will be the K will be two I just have
两个分为两组a和B.
two partitioning into two sets a and B
所以我只是K是仅有2好是什么
so I just K is just 2 okay what's the
算法好，如果我选择了一个
algorithm well if if I've chosen a
分区A的和B的有
partition the A's and the B's have
将它们分开然后告诉我什么
separated them then that tells me what
X和y应该是，但现在是什么
the X and the y should be but now what
我会做下一个，所以这将是一个
do I do next so is this going to be a
我现在是一个交替的分区
sort of an alternating partition now I
采取这两个质心，所以第一步
take those two centroids so so step one
是原谅YZ和B找到他们的
is forgiven YZ and B's find their
质心X和什么和那个基本的
centroids X and what and that elementary
然后第二步给出了
then the second step is given the
给出那些位置的质心x和y
centroids x and y given those positions
给定x和y它们不会是质心
given x and y they won't be centroids
一旦你看到x发生了什么
once when you see what happens given x
和y
and y
我们形成最好的分区
we do we form form the best partition
最好的集群好吧，所以我们有一步
best clusters okay so step one we we had
猜测最好的集群是什么
a guess at what the best clusters were
我们现在找到了他们的质心
and we found their centroids now we
从质心开始，我们形成新的
start with the centroids and we form new
再次集群，如果这些集群是
clusters again and if these clusters are
和我们开始时一样
the same as the ones we started with
与他们然后算法有
with them then the algorithm has
融合但可能不会是这些
converged but probably won't be these
集群所以你必须告诉我什么
clusters so you'll have to tell me what
如果我是最好的集群，我的意思是什么
what I mean by the best clusters if I'm
如果我有两点x和y我
if I've got the two points x and y I
想要我要分开的所有点
want the points I want to separate all
围绕X聚集到该点
the points that cluster around X to the
那些聚集在Y周围的人然后他们
ones that cluster around Y and then they
可能与我原来的不同
probably different from my original
从现在开始我现在有了新的东西，我再说一遍
start so now I've got new now I repeat
第一步，但让我们想想怎么做
step one so but let's just think how do
我形成最佳群以及我坐
i form the best clusters well I take a
点，我必须决定它是否去
point and I have to decide does it go
与X或它在X去
with X or does it go with in the X
群集或它是否进入群集
cluster or does it go in the cluster
在Y附近，我该怎么做才决定
around Y so how do I decide that just
无论哪一个都接近每一个
whichever one is closer to so each each
要与每个节点一起使用II
point goes with each node you should I I
可以说每个节点都跟着
could say each node goes with the the
更接近x和y
closer of x and y
应该是那样的点
so points that should have been that are
现在我们要接近X了
closer to X now we're going to put them
在X周围的集群中，并做到这一点
in the cluster around X and does that
解决问题
solve the problem
不，因为它可能，但它可能
no because well it might but it might
不是我们要回来一个步骤
not the we have to come back to step one
我们现在已经改变了他们的集群
we've now changed their clusters they'll
有不同的质心，所以我们重复
have different centroids so we repeat
第一步找到他们的质心
step one find their centroids for the
然后我们来两个新的集群
two new clusters then we come to step
两个找到应该配合的
two find the ones that should go with
两个质心来回我
the two centroids and back and forth I
不知道我不认为有一个很好的
don't know I don't think there's a nice
收敛理论或收益率
theory of convergence or rate of
收敛所有这个问题
convergence all the questions that this
当然总是问，但这是非常的
course is always asking but it's a very
流行算法K-机构K将
popular algorithm k-means K would be to
有K群可以，所以我不是
have K clusters okay so that's a I'm not
去讨论我宁愿讨论
going to discuss the I'd rather discuss
其他一些方法来解决这个问题
some other ways to do this to solve this
问题，但这是一种黑客
problem but that's one sort of hack that
工作得很好，所以第二种方法
works quite well okay so second approach
是下一秒才会到来的
is is what it's coming next second
解决方法，它被称为
solution method and it's called the
谱聚类
spectral clustering
这是方法的名称和之前的名称
that's the name of the method and before
我记下你做什么做什么的
I write down what you do what does the
字光谱意味着你看到光谱
word spectral mean you see spectral
图论谱谱聚类与in
graph theory spectral clustering and in
你看到的其他数学部分
other parts of mathematics you see that
你在哪里看到我给出的谱定理
where you see spectral theorem I gave
你最多，我把它描述为
you the most and I described it as the
最重要的也许是线性定理
most important perhaps theorem in linear
代数中至少有一个是前三名
algebra at least one of the top three is
所以我会把它写在这里，因为它是
so I'll write it over here because it's
不是这不是它是一样的
not it doesn't this is a it's the same
字谱很好让我问一下
word spectral well let me ask the
再问一下这个词是什么
question again what's that word spectral
什么意思是手段
about what does that mean that means
如果我有一个矩阵，我想
that if I have a matrix and I want to
说说它的频谱是什么
talk about its spectrum what is the
矩阵的光谱就是它
spectrum of the matrix it is the the
特征值因此谱理论谱
eigenvalues so spectral theory spectral
聚类使用的是特征值
clustering is using the eigenvalues of
一些矩阵就是那个光谱
some matrix that's what that spectral is
告诉我是的光谱定理
telling me yeah so the spectral theorem
当然是对称矩阵
of course is that for a symmetric matrix
特征值是真实的和
s the eigenvalues are real and the
特征向量是正交的而不是
eigenvectors are orthogonal and don't
忘记真实的完整陈述是什么
forget what the real full statement is
在这里，因为可能会重复
here because there could be repeated
真正的特征值和什么是
real eigenvalues and what does the
谱定理告诉我对称性
spectral theorem tell me for symmetric
如果lambda等于5则为矩阵
matrices if that if lambda equal five is
如果它是四次，则重复四次
repeated four times if it's a four times
给出的等式的解
solution of the equation that gives
特征值那么结论是什么
eigenvalues then what's the conclusion
然后有四个独立的
then there are four independent
我正交
orthogonal I
矢量与它一起去我们不能这么说
vectors to go with it we can't say that
关于矩阵
about matrices
关于所有矩阵，但我们可以说
about all matrices but we can say it
关于所有对称矩阵，事实上
about all symmetric matrices and in fact
这些本征矢量是正交的，以便
those eigenvectors are orthogonal so
我们甚至会说更多我们能找到的东西
we're even saying more we can find for
与a一起使用的正交特征向量
orthogonal eigenvectors that go with a
与特征值的多重好吗
with a multiplicity for eigenvalues okay
这是光谱定理谱
that's spectral theorem spectral
聚类开始于
clustering starts with the with the
图拉普拉斯矩阵我记得
graph laplacian matrix may I remember
那个矩阵是什么因为那是
what that matrix is because that's the
这是线性的关键连接
that's the key connection of linear
代数到图论是
algebra to graph theory is the
此图拉普利安的属性
properties of this graph laplacian
矩阵好吧让我说L为
matrix okay so let me say L for
laplacian使矩阵单向
laplacian so that matrix one way to
将它描述为转置a
describe it is as a transpose a where a
是曲线图的关联矩阵或
is the incidence matrix of the graph or
我们将看到的另一种方式是D
another way we'll see is two is the D
对角线的度矩阵
the degree matrix that's diagonal
我会举一个例子来提醒一下
and I'll do an example just to remind
你-我不知道我叫什么
you - the I don't know what I've called
这个我应该叫它为B.
this one shall I call it B for the
那个时刻和B是什么矩阵
moment and what matrix is B that's the
邻接矩阵真的你应该知道
adjacency matrix really you should know
这四个矩阵他们是关键的四个
these four matrices they're the key four
与任何图形相关联的矩阵
matrices associated with any graph the
入射矩阵是M个n行边缘
incidence matrix that's M by n row edges
和节点边缘和节点，所以它
and nodes edges and nodes so it's
矩形，但我正在形成一个转置
rectangular but I'm forming a transpose
我在这里，所以我形成一个对称的
ru here so I'm forming a symmetric
正半定矩阵
positive semi definite matrix
所以这个小花朵是对称的
so this this little blossom is symmetric
积极的半明确是的，让我让
positive semi definite yeah let me let
我只记得所有这些矩阵
me just recall what all these matrices
是为了一个简单的图表
are for for a simple graph
好的，所以我只是画一个图表好吧
okay so I'll just draw a graph alright
好吧所以发生率矩阵有1个
okay so the incidence matrix there are 1
2345个边缘所以5行有4个
2 3 4 5 edges so 5 rows there are 4
节点123和4所以4列和a
nodes 1 2 3 and 4 so 4 columns and a
典型的行将是边缘1
typical row would be edge 1 going from
节点1到节点2所以它会有一个
node 1 to node 2 so it would have a
减1和1在那里，让我采取
minus 1 and a 1 there and let me take
它的两个从1到3节点，所以我们
its two going from 1 to node 3 so we'd
那里有一个减1和1
have a minus 1 and a 1 there so so
这就是发生率矩阵，确定是什么
that's the incidence matrix a ok what's
程度矩阵很简单
the degree matrix that's simple
度数矩阵a转置a
the degree matrix well a transpose a
这是Mbyn这是n由M所以它是
this is M by n this is n by M so it's
在这种情况下，它通过n确定4乘4
it's n by n ok in this case 4 by 4 so
度矩阵将是4乘4和
the degree matrix will be 4 by 4 and by
他和它会告诉我们的程度
him and it will tell us the degree of
这意味着我们只计算它
that which means which we just count the
边缘所以它的3个边缘没有23
edges so it's 3 edges going in no 2 3
进入节点3的边只有2条边
edges going in node 3 has just 2 edges
并且节点4只有2条边缘
and node 4 has just 2 edges it so that's
程度矩阵然后是邻接
the degree matrix and then the adjacency
我称之为B的矩阵也是4乘4
matrix that I've called B is also 4 by 4
它是什么告诉我们哪个节点是
and what is it it tells us which node is
连接到哪个节点所以我不这样做
connected to which node so and I don't
允许节点边缘
allow nodes edges
将O连接到自身以使其为零
that connect an O to itself so zeros on
对角线
the diagonal
连接到哪个节点的数量
how many so which nodes are connected to
节点一井两个和四个
node one well all of two and four and
三个连接到一个所以我有
three are connected to one so I have
那三个节点都没有
ones there no to all three nodes are
连接-不-所以我会有第二个
connected - no - so I'll have the second
列和行将包含所有三个
column and row will have all three ones
怎么没有三个没关系只边缘
how about no three okay only only edges
只有两条边连接到
only two edges are connected only to
只有两个节点连接到三个节点
only two nodes are connected to three
一，二，但不是四，一，二
one and two but not four so one and two
我有，但不是四个好，所以这是
I have but not four okay so that's the
邻接矩阵就是这么认为的
adjacency matrix is that right think so
这是度矩阵是这样的
this is the degree matrix this is the
关联矩阵和该公式给出
incidence matrix and that formula gives
我laplacian好吧，让我们写一下
me the laplacian okay let's just write
如果我使用了laplacian那么
down the laplacian so if I use the
度减去B中，很容易的
degree minus B that that's easy the
度数是332和2现在我有这些
degrees were 3 3 2 & 2 now I have these
弊端和那些0好的
minuses and those those were 0 ok
这是一个积极的半明确
so that's a positive semi-definite
矩阵是一个正定矩阵
matrix is it a positive definite matrix
所以我们会让我问你是不是很奇怪
so we'll let me ask you is it singular
或者它不是单数
or is it not singular
是否在其零空间或中有一个向量
is there a vector in its null space or
它的零空间中没有向量
is there not a vector in its null space
你可以解决dx等于全零和
can you solve d x equals all zeroes and
当然，你们每个人都可以看到这一点
of course you can everybody sees that
所有人的矢量将是一个
the vector of all ones will be a
解决D到2l我很抱歉我应该
solution to D to 2l I'm sorry I should
在这里说LLx等于0Lx等于
be saying L here L x equals 0 L x equals
0表示一维的整行
0 for a whole line of a one-dimensional
并且L的零空间具有维度
and the null space of L is has dimension
1它有一个基础向量1111和
1 it's got one basis vector 1 1 1 1 and
这将永远发生在a
that will always happen with a with a
使用我创建的图表设置
with the graph set up that I've created
好的，这是第一个事实
ok so that's the first fact that this
正半正定矩阵Las
positive semi definite matrix L as
lambda1等于0，特征向量为
lambda 1 equals 0 and the eigenvector is
常数cccc是一维特征
constant cccc the one-dimensional eigen
空间或1111是典型的
space or 1 1 1 1 is a typical
特征向量现在回到图表
eigenvector ok now back to graph
将图的概念聚类为图
clustering the idea of graph a graph
集群是看费德勒
clustering is to look at the Fiedler
本征矢量这就是所谓的X2是
eigen vector this is called X 2 is the
下一个特征向量是
next eigenvector is the
最小的特征向量
the eigenvector for the smallest
λmin的正特征值
positive eigenvalue for lambda min
排除0所以最小的特征值
excluding 0 so the smallest eigenvalue
l最小特征值及其特征值
of l the smallest eigenvalue and its
特征向量这被称为Fiedler
eigenvector this is called the Fiedler
以捷克命名的矢量
vector named after the Czech
数学家伟大伟大的人
mathematician a great great a great man
在线性代数中，他研究了这一点
in linear algebra and he studied this
矢量这种情况所以每个人
vector this situation so everybody who
知道laplacian知道的图形
knows about the graph laplacian is aware
它的第一个特征值为零，
that its first eigenvalue is zero and
下一个特征值是重要的
that the next eigenvalue is is important
是啊
yeah
拉普拉斯方程式是的，所以是的
to Laplace's equation yes so yeah that's
一个好问题，为什么这个名字的名字
a good question so why the word the name
拉普拉斯马马虎虎
laplacian so-so
是啊，这是一个很好的问题，因此
yeah that's a good question so the
熟悉的东西，所以它连接到
familiar thing so it connects to
拉普拉斯的有限差分方程
Laplace's finite difference equation
因为我们在谈论矩阵
because we're talking about matrices
这里而不是衍生品而不是功能
here and not derivatives not functions
那么为什么laplacian这个词如果我如此
so why the word laplacian well so if I
如果我的图表是合成的，那就有规律
have a regular if my graph is composed
这样就有一个包含25个节点的图形
of so there's a graph with with 25 nodes
这是4倍520约40
and 4 times 5 20 about 40 this is
可能有大约40个边和25个节点
probably has about 40 edges and 25 nodes
当然我可以构建它的图形
and of course I can construct its graph
所有这四个矩阵都是它的
all those four matrices for it it's it's
关联矩阵的度矩阵
incidence matrix its degree matrix of
学位将适用于所有这些
the degree will be for at all these
内部点数度为3点
inside points the degree will be 3 at
这些边界点的程度将是
these boundary points the degree will be
2在这些角落但是什么
2 at these corner points but the what
将矩阵L看起来像那么还等什么
will the matrix L look like so so what
是L，这将告诉你它为什么
is L and that will tell you why it has
这个名字laplacian所以矩阵L会
this name laplacian so the matrix L will
有4个权利的学位将在
have the degree 4 right will be on the
对角线来自D另一个
diagonal that's coming from D the other
减去的是来自的
the minus ones that come from be the
邻接矩阵将与。相关联
adjacency matrix will be associated with
这些节点否则全部为零，从而
those nodes and otherwise all zeros so
这是L的典型行
this is a typical row of L
Elle的典型角色以此为中心
typical role of Elle centered at that
节点也许那个节点号为510
node so maybe that's node number five 10
这将是25个中的13个
13 that's 13 out of 25 that would would
告诉你这个，对不起那些
show you this and that sorry those are
减去那些减去那么一个4a4
minus ones minus ones so a 4 a 4 in the
在对角线和4减去那些
on the diagonal and 4 minus ones that's
图表的模型问题
the model problem for when the graph is
一个网格方格，你是否关联
a grid square grid and do you associate
拉普拉斯方程所以这是
that with Laplace's equation so this is
这就是拉普拉斯的原因
the this is the reason that the Laplace
为什么加号会因为而加入呢？
why why the plus gets in it because
拉普拉斯方程的微分
Laplace's equation the differential
方程式是二阶导数
equation is second derivative with
尊重x平方和第二个
respect to x squared and the second
导数特殊y平方为0
derivative the special y squared is 0
我们这里有什么为Lu等于0
and what we have here is L u equals 0
它是矢量的离散拉普拉斯
it's discrete laplacian the vector
laplacian图拉普拉斯所在的地方
laplacian the graph laplacian where the
第二个X衍生物被减去
second X derivative is replaced by minus
1至-1和第二Y衍生物
1 to minus 1 and the second Y derivative
由-1减1秒代替
is replaced by minus 1 to minus 1 second
X和y的差异
differences in the X and the y
方向，所以是的，所以这是
directions so that's yeah so that's the
这就是laplace的解释
that's the explanation for laplace it's
离散的laplace离散或
a discrete laplace discrete or the
有限差分拉普拉斯现在好了
finite difference Laplace okay now to
我必须告诉你什么是什么
finish I have to tell you what the what
群集如何决定群集
clusters how do you decide the clusters
从L如何提出两个集群
from L how does L propose two clusters
A和B的，而且这里是
the A's and the B's and and here's the
回答他们来自这个特征向量
answer they come from this eigenvector
你看到的fiedler特征向量
the fiedler eigenvectors you look at
那个特征向量
that eigenvector
它有一些积极的和一些消极的
it's got some positive and some negative
组件具有正面的组件
components the components with positive
这个特征向量的数量所以
numbers of this eigenvector so the
积极的X的积极成分
positive the positive components of X so
这个特征向量的这种耶和
of this yeah of this eigenvector and
这有负面的组成部分
there are negative components of this
特征向量和那两个
eigenvector and those are the two
群集，所以这就是群集
clusters so there so it's the cluster is
这两个集群是由
the two clusters are decided by the
特征向量由符号加或减
eigenvector by the signs plus or minus
组件的标志加号
signs of the components the plus signs
去1，减号进入
going 1 and the minus signs go into
另一个，你必须尝试
another and you have to experiment to
看到那会成功我不知道
see that that would succeed I don't know
它实际上会做些什么
what it would do on this actually
因为几乎没有分裂成两个
because that's hardly splits up into two
我想也许是分裂
I suppose maybe the split is along a
这样或那样的线来得到我
line like that or something to to get I
不知道那是什么聚类
don't know what clustering that's that
这不是一个自然的图表
this is not a graph that is naturally
群集但你仍然可以做两个
clustered but you could still do two
它的k-means你仍然可以做
k-means on it you could still do
光谱聚类，你会发现
spectral clustering and you would find
这个特征向量现在有什么意义
this eigenvector now what's the point
关于这个特征向量，我将完成
about this eigenvector there I'll finish
在一瞬间我们对此了解多少
in one moment what do we know about that
特征向量与那个相比
eigenvector as compared to that one so
这是一个特征向量，所有人都让我
here was an eigenvector all ones let me
只是使它在所有的一个一个一个一个一个
just make it all one one one one one in
该照片在这里是25周的人是一对
that picture it's 25 ones here's a the
下一个特征向量和什么是
next eigenvector up and what's the
这两个特征向量之间的关系
relation between those two eigenvectors
升它们是正交
of L they are orthogonal
这些是对称的特征向量
these are eigenvectors of a symmetric
矩阵因此它们是正交的
matrix so they're orthogonal so that
意味着与这个家伙正交
means to be orthogonal to this guy
意味着您的组件添加到零
means that your components added to zero
右边的矢量与所有的矢量正交
right a vector is orthogonal to all ones
这个点积只是加起来的
that dot product is just add up the
组件所以我们有一堆
components so we have a bunch of
积极的组成部分和一堆
positive components and a bunch of
负面成分他们有相同
negative components they have the same
总和，因为因为点积与
sum because because the dot product with
那是零和那两个组成部分
that is zero and those two components
这两组组件是你的
those two sets of components are your to
告诉你光谱中的两个星团
tell you the two clusters in spectral
集群所以它非常漂亮
clustering so it's a pretty nifty
它确实要求你计算一个算法
algorithm it does ask you to compute an
特征向量，当然需要
eigen vector and that of course takes
时间，然后有三分之一以上
time and then there's a third more
直接算法来做到这一点
direct algorithm to to do this
实际上有优化问题
optimization problem well actually there
这是一个很重要的问题
are many this is an important problem so
有很多提出的算法很好
there are many proposed algorithms good
好吧，我正在关闭那里有一场决赛
okay I'm closing up there was a final
对于k-means肯定是肯定的
question yeah well certainly for k-means
现在，如果我不得不做三个集群
now if i had to do three clusters with
fiedler我会看前三个
fiedler i would look at the first three
特征向量和第一个
eigenvectors and well the first one
就什么都不是，我会看看
would be nothing and i would look at the
接下来的两个，这将很漂亮
next two and that would be pretty
如果我想要六个集群，那就成功了
successful if I wanted six clusters it
可能会在脱落
probably would fall off in in the
在聚类的质量是的，但
quality of the the clustering yeah but
当然我会看看
that certainly I would look at the
最低六个特征向量并得到
lowest six eigenvectors and get
在某个地方是的，所以没关系，所以这是一个
somewhere yeah right so okay so that's a
话题重要话题我有点标准
topic important topic I sort of standard
应用图论中的主题没关系
topic in applied graph theory okay so
说你星期三我希望我希望
say your Wednesday I'm hoping I'm hoping
星期三所以阿德尔曼教授有
on Wednesday so professor Adelman has
告诉我一个新的，最佳的方式来看待
told me a new and optimal way to look at
反向传播你的问题
the problem of back propagation you
如果你记得回传
remember back propagation if you
记住你没有的讲座
remember the lecture on it you don't
难道你不想记住
don't you don't want to remember the
讲授它，它
lecture on it it
这是一个棘手的杂乱的事情
it's it's a tricky messy thing to
解释，但他说，如果我解释它
explain but he says if I explain it
在线性代数中使用Julia就是这样
using Julia in linear algebra it's it's
如此清晰，我们会给他一个机会
clear so we'll give him a chance on
周三表明那一点
Wednesday to show that that
革命性的方法
revolutionary approach to to the
反向传播的解释和I.
explanation of back propagation and I
希望我告诉他他可以有一半
hope for I told him he could have half
一个小时，项目需要一些
an hour and projects would take some
我希望现在我们不得不狂野
time I hope now we've had to with wild
掌声所以我希望我们能得到更多
applause so I hope we get a couple more
在我们上一节课上好的，请看星期三
in our last class okay see you Wednesday
如果你有好的话，如果你带好
and if you bring well if you have
项目准备好在线发送给我
projects ready send them to me online
也许打印输出也是如此
and maybe a printout as well that would
如果你没有准备就好，那就太棒了
be terrific if you don't have them ready
他们可以按小时去信封
by the hour they can go the envelope
在我办公室外面会收到它们
outside my office would receive them
good so I'll see you Wednesday for the
好的，所以周三我会见到你的
最后一堂课
final class